Guide to the Louis Simon papers, 1936-1981
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Louis Simon papers
1936-1981
C0223
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
0.25 linear feet (1 box)
The Louis Simon papers contain newspaper clippings, photographs, programs, and correspondence relating to Federal Theatre in New Jersey and New York.
Simon, Louis M.
Scope and Content
The Louis Simon papers contain newspaper clippings, photographs, programs, and correspondence relating to Federal Theatre in New Jersey and New York.
Biographical Information
Louis M. Simon worked for the Federal Theatre Project as New Jersey State Director and later as Production Director in New York State.
The Federal Theatre Project was a division of the Works Progress Administration (WPA), which provided employment for large numbers of artists, writers, and performers during the Great Depression (1929-1939). The Federal Theatre began in 1935 and, until its end in 1939, flourished as the first and only federally sponsored and subsidized theater program in the United States. Directed by Hallie Flanagan (1880-1969), it was a way for theatrical professionals to gain employment during the Depression. Jobs were provided for many people, including actors, playwrights, scene designers, scene builders, seamstresses, lighting experts, ushers, box-office men, and stagehands.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Louis Simon to Special Collections and Archives October 25, 1976.
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as numerous other personal papers.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by folder title.
Index Terms
Persons:
Simon, Louis M.
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
New Deal, 1933-1939.; Theater--United States.
Contents List
- Louis Simon papers, 1936-1981
  - Archives of American Art, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beggar's Opera; letter to Duke Ellington, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and papers. Identification cards; correspondence between Louis Simon and Hallie Flanagan regarding the movie Run Little Children, the municipal and the music theatres and The Trial of Dr. Beck.
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Letter from Hal Smith; handwritten notes.
  - Newspaper clippings - Children's theatre, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings - New Jersey Federal Theatre, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings - New York State Federal Theatre; production bulletin, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings - The Trial of Dr. Beck (photocopies), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings; drawing; program (Adele Nathan Gutman), 1937; 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Six photographs (one black and white, five color) of a New Jersey production of The Emperor's New Clothes.
  - Programs, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Programs: Nine Pine Street; The Playboy of the Western World; Treasure Island; The Trial of Dr. Beck; Birds; Gentlemen Prefer Blondes.
  - The Trial of Dr. Beck (revival), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)